

Muhammad Mahad Ashraf

Senior Software Engineer (Backend)

× +92.303.7477773

mmahadashraf@gmail.com

Pakistan Town, Islamabad, Pakistan

Summary

I'm a seasoned backend developer with 11 years of experience in the industry working expensively in PHP. I have expertise in Laravel, CakePHP, Codeigniter, Node.js, bash scripting and server orchestration via Digital Ocean APIs and jenkins, Amazon AWS, Terraform & Ansible

Skills

Amazon AWS | Ansible | Atlassian Jira | Bash | CakePHP | Codeigniter | Git | Jquery | Laravel | Linux System | Node.js |

Power Electronic Knowledge | Server orchestration via Digital Ocean APIs and Jenkins | Shopify Payments App | Terraform | Vagrant | WP CLI

Experience



Oct 2019 - Present Senior Software Engineer (Backend)

Embrace IT, Islamabad, Pakistan

Development in PHP Laravel. REST APIs. Designing and implementing infrastructures and CI/CD workflows using Github actions, Terraform, Ansible, AWS/ Digital Ocean, Cypress. Development & support for AltaPay Payment Gateway plugins, Shopify Apps, SDKs and resources in various programming languages.

Apr 2018 - Sep 2019



Team Lead / Senior Software Engineer

Xeeonix Technologies Ltd, Islamabad, Pakistan

My experience here includes working in custom PHP, CakePHP, Node.js, bash scripting, dev ops, server orchestration via Digital Ocean APIs and jenkins. I was responsible for leading a team of backend developers, interacting and handling multiple clients and sometimes supervising frontend, backend, db development, testing and software architecture in other MERN stack projects and products too.

Jun 2015 - Mar 2018



₩eb Programmer

MediaLinkers Pvt. Ltd, Islamabad, Pakistan

Worked extensively in Laravel, Codeigniter, custom PHP. My responsibilities along with the team were to develop and maintain over 250 (and growing) websites, optimise code and SQL, develop and test centralised solutions. Implemented payment gateways 3rd party APIs, and developed REST APIs as well. Worked on efficiently generating different kinds of reports after data analysis.

Nov 2013 - Jun 2015



Junior Software Engineer

WDNEC, Islamabad, Pakistan

Worked in custom PHP, implemented different payment gateway integrations. Built websites for domain registration, email server setup with APIs, VPN solutions with PPTP, L2TP, OpenVPN. WHMCS module development and customization. Wrote web services, built few cross platform apps using apache cordova, phonegap, jquery mobile.

Education

2014



International Islamic University

Bachelors in Science, BS in Software Engineering DAD, Web Development, SE

CGPA: 3.28/4

Projects

AltaPay

https://github.com/AltaPay

Development & support for AltaPay Payment Gateway plugins, Shopify Apps, SDKs and resources in various programming languages.

E-Build Pakistan

https://ebuildpakistan.com

Pakistan's first construction industry e-commerce website. Laravel, postgresql, AWS S3, Lambda, RDS, DynamoDB

iDictate

http://www.idictate.com

Transcription solutions. CakePHP. Bash Scripting. Amazon S3.

Virtual Doorman

http://www.virtualdoorman.com

Building security system. Custom PHP, Slim, REST APIs

Bazze

http://www.bazze.io

Laravel. VPN solution. REST APIs.

MSD

http://www.monthlyshoppingdollars.com

Codeignitor, payment gateways, 3rd party APIs, Reporting.

Languages

Punjabi	English	Urdu
Expert	Expert	Expert